<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft365 on diecknet</title>
    <link>https://diecknet.de/en/tags/microsoft365/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft365 on diecknet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://diecknet.de/en/tags/microsoft365/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate Exchange Online with Azure Automation in 2024</title>
      <link>https://diecknet.de/en/2023/01/09/Exchange-Online-per-Azure-Automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diecknet.de/en/2023/01/09/Exchange-Online-per-Azure-Automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you want to manage Exchange Online via Azure Automation, &lt;strong&gt;Managed Identities&lt;/strong&gt; is what you should use (this statement was last checked in June 2024).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy-approach&#34;&gt;Legacy approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, RunAs Accounts or Plaintext Credentials (🤢) were also commonly used for this purpose, but this is now considered deprecated. RunAs accounts will be  discontinued by fall 2023. And I don&amp;rsquo;t have to say anything about plaintext passwords, do I?
You could still use App Registrations in Entra ID, but if you really just want to automate some Exchange settings via Azure Automation, it&amp;rsquo;s not really necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office 365 Trial Licenses</title>
      <link>https://diecknet.de/en/2020/06/10/Office-365-Trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diecknet.de/en/2020/06/10/Office-365-Trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can register for a free Office 365/Microsoft 365 Tenant to try it out. Or you can add trial licenses to your existing tenant. You&amp;rsquo;ll get a 30 day trial phase. The trial contains 25 user licenses. After the expiration of the trial phase, you can delete the tenant or extend the trial. Alternatively you can purchase licenses to continue to use the services.
A list of links to the trial licenes is further below in this article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange Online: Apple Internet Accounts - Need admin approval</title>
      <link>https://diecknet.de/en/2020/05/10/Apple-Internet-Accounts-Office365/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diecknet.de/en/2020/05/10/Apple-Internet-Accounts-Office365/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the first users logged into Office 365 with his iPhone to sync his Contacts and Calendar, he got this dialogue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need admin approval&lt;/strong&gt;
Apple Internet Accounts
Apple Internet Accounts needs permission to access resources in your organization that only an admin can grant. Please ask an admin to grant permission to this app before you can use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, the app used to be called &amp;ldquo;iOS Accounts&amp;rdquo; and was apparently renamed in early 2020. However, the previous AppID has remained the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
